Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/kirthee (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Benefits Negotiation
Sourcing
Internet Recruiting

Kirthee Panuganti

Recruiter - Talent Sourcing at Microsoft Hyderabad

Summary

Technical / Engineering recruiter by profession and passion. Handson experience in hiring across Product development, E-commerce & consulting organisations.

Extensive experience in hiring Engineering managers, Development Managers, SDE's and SDET's. Stakeholder Management • End to end recruitment life cycle for high end technology streams.

Experience

Microsoft

Sr. Recruiter - Talent Sourcing March 2020 - Present (6 months)

Deloitte India (Offices of the US)

4 years 9 months

Lead Technical Recruiter

September 2018 - May 2019 (9 months)

Hyderabad Area, India

- Was hired to play a significant role in staffing the Product Development groups in Deloitte (Ilabs, Bersin and Converge health)
- Responsible for Senior hiring, Niche Hiring, SDET's, Architects, Project Managers, UX designers and Info security.
- · Worked with Global stakeholders
- Handled end to end recruitment life cycle (sourcing, screening and offer management)
- Hired across different job families (Development, testing, Program Management and Networking)
- Planned and executed an order board of 300+ open postilions across 15 different skills.
- Worked as an advisor to the business, providing an in-depth understanding of the talent market and trends.

- Manage & work with recruiting team members to develop, implement, and execute hiring strategy for multiple requisitions.
- Trained and coached new and junior recruitment specialists to improve quality of hires across all business sectors.

Senior Technical Recruiter September 2014 - August 2018 (4 years)

Hyderabad Area, India

- Planned and executed recruiting activities that result in the hiring of the right talent into all levels for lateral hire.
- Worked with a cross-border tech staffing leadership teams to share best practices across APAC and globally.
- Developed and implemented cost effective sourcing mix, including those of online, internal, direct, and referrals.
- Managed recruitment agencies and ensuring that the best of the results is delivered in the most cost and time effectively.

Amazon

Recruiter II

September 2013 - July 2014 (11 months)

Chennai Area, India

- Managed complete recruiting process (from sourcing to On-boarding) for multiple skillsets at Amazon kindle development team and ensured a smooth and positive candidate experience.
- Monitoring metrics and reports for the different business units on weekly basis.
- Partner with hiring managers and teams and conduct reviews to assess talent requirement and gain insights to the hiring needs.
- Effectively screened candidates within the framework of the position specification.

Microsoft

Recruiter

April 2007 - September 2013 (6 years 6 months)

Hyderabad

- Involved in the End to end Recruitment process.
- Hired for Principal/regional portfolio Managers.
- Contracting with business in terms of Requisition filling and hiring processes.
- Planned & Executed recruitment Drives with a goal to achieve 100% CSAT and HSAT.

- Sending out the weekly reports and attending client meetings for Hiring discussions.
- E-rec/ Rec web adoption and consistently being green on Metrics.
- Follow up and Follow through the offer candidates till they come on board and facilitate smooth on boarding.

Education

Manipal Institute of Technology
M.B.A, Marketing, Human resources · (2003 - 2006)

Boddu krishna collage of commerce Bcom, Commerce · (1997 - 2000)